Anastasia Oparysheva

Data Engineer

Data engineer with professional experience 1+ year of DWH development. Passion about databases and enjoy customized analysis, refinement and refactoring of existing ETL/ELT processes, DBMS. Development of new download streams on different layers of the DWH using Airflow. Work with different data sources such as Oracle, PostgreSQL. Highly motivated to solve challenging tasks and learn new technologies and tools if the need arises.

EXPERIENCE

SBER, Moscow

Data Engineer

Aug, 2021 - Present

- > Sber is the largest bank and digital ecosystem in Russia. Here I work with sources such as Oracle and completed more than 100TB of data at Data Lake in clusters based on Cloudera and developed incremental loading for 50GB for Data Cloud with ETL4Hadoop (Python, Spark).
- > Created a new method to load data faster from Oracle source.
- > Created custom SQL query for Data Quality (SQL, Scala) that improved automation check.
- > Proactively **improved** instrument ETL4Hadoop: wrote and structured documentations.

Digital League, Moscow

Data Quality Analyst

Mar, 2021 - Aug, 2021

- > Digital League is one of the largest system integrators in Russia. Developed scripts on SQL to control Data Quality to prevent incidents on DWH.
- > Involved in the process of incoming requests to repair incorrect data for the business.
- > Lead business conversation with the Customer based on quality checking results.

Siblion, Moscow

Siebel Developer

Oct, 2018 - Mar, 2020

- Siblion is the system integration company with Siebel CRM. Developed B2B process marketing, developed functional for client maintenance.
- > Created integration process using Siebel Tools, Workflow, EAI Data Transformation, EAI XML Convertor, Inbound/Outbound web-services, Open UI and standards usability Siebel CRM.
- > Developed screen form and existing functional in screen forms with Siebel Tools.

EDUCATION

Russian University of Humanities

Master's degree, Software and cognitive support of intellectual robots and programming of intellectual systems Sep, 2018 - Jul, 2020

Moscow, Russia

Science research in the Dorodnicyn Computing Centre. Lead in the development of intellectual robotics in simulation GAZEBO. We created a simulation of computer vision, manipulating environment objects and mechanical movements of the prototype of Shakey the Robot.

Russian University of Humanities

Bachelor's degree, Software and cognitive support of intellectual robots and programming of intellectual systems

Sep, 2014 - Jul, 2018

Moscow, Russia

CONTACTS

LinkedIn XING Telegram GitHub

SKILLS

SQL

Hadoop
Python
ETL
Apache Spark
Git
Open-mindedness
Emotional Intelligence
Teamwork

LANGUAGES

Russian - Native English - Intermediate Spanish - Basic

INTERESTS

Bicycle
Surfing
Ping-Pong
Travels
Languages
Film Photos
Oil Painting